The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
3 years later
Senior,
I’m leaving seclusion.
You don't have to worry,
I have memorized the Underworld Ascension Method
and the technique to locate extreme Yin energy gathering spots.
I will find a suitable place to cultivate.
I’m sorry for dragging you into this.
When you helped me,
you used too much of your Origin Soul's energy.
If you hadn't, you wouldn't be in this state.
I will form my Golden Core.
Wait for me.
You will wake up,
right ?
It's been 100 years...
Master...
you abandoned your corpse last time.
But this time,
you won’t escape !
Zi Daren\NWu Yu's Corpse Puppet\NMiddle stage Nascent Soul
The Yin energy is dense here.
Village ruins
Steamed buns for sale !
Scram !
It was destroyed in a single night
and an extreme Yin energy gathering spot was created by these countless deaths...
Grade 1\NUnderworld Yin
The maze formation is complete.
The Underworld Ascension Method has 9 layers.
Every 3 layers requires you
to open the meridians for the Dantian, Qi Sea, and the ancestral meridian.
This is called meridian awakening.
The success rate of meridian awakening
is heavily influenced by the quality of the Yin energy.
When a meridian awakening succeeds,
a Cold Core will be condensed.
With that Cold Core,
your spiritual energy will become cold spiritual energy.
Finally, by merging the 3 Cold Cores,
you will have a chance to reach Core Formation directly.
Adai\NLate stage Foundation Establishment
Who dares to trespass ?
Still not leaving ?
You're courting death !
Shit !
I can’t retrieve it...
What kind of technique is this ?
Its healing effect is extraordinary...
Who are you ?
If you leave now
and stop interrupting my cultivation,
I’ll let this matter slide.
Now stay out of my way.
And if you don't,
I will destroy you.
You mean this formation ?
The talismans on this guy's body are weird.
I must avoid conflict...
You’re courting death !
Thousand Illusions Bead
This is an artifact !
Core Formation ?
This is…
an illusion artifact.
Nascent Soul !
These illusions are very realistic.
The more spiritual energy flows into the bead,
the higher the illusory cultivation level becomes.
It's difficult to see through it
so it's perfect
for intimidation.
This guy is weird
for trading such an artifact
against a minor maze formation.
I should find a better cultivation spot.
Grade 5\NUnderworld Yin
This place is different,
the Yin energy is far denser than elsewhere.
Begin meridian awakening !
Wang Lin doesn’t know that
his spiritual energy
is being affected by the extreme Yin conditions
and is slowly evolving towards the Ji Realm.
The main reason this is happening
is that the Underworld Ascension Method
is one of the rare techniques
capable of cultivating Ji Realm spiritual energy.
In the Underworld Ascension Method,
each meridian awakening gets more difficult.
I must find an even better extreme Yin energy gathering spot.
It's been a century,
I never thought you’d gain sentience.
I can spare you
but you will have to use your bond with Master
to help me locate his Nascent Soul.
Let’s go,
take me to him.
If you can find Master’s Nascent Soul,
I’ll devour it and gain my freedom.
And you might evolve into a Corpse Demon.
Grade 2\NUnderworld Yin
It's still Underworld Yin level...
You’ve been following me this whole time,
what do you want ?
Do you want me to follow you ?
This statue
looks like it's alive.
Grade 10\NUnderworld Yin
This extreme Yin energy gathering spot
is Grade 10 Underworld Yin !
5 days later
I have already mastered the 5th layer of the Underworld Ascension Method.
I have found you...
Young friend, don’t act rashly.
This old man means no harm.
Adai,
don’t be rude to our guest.
Wu Yu's Nascent Soul
Master...
It's been 100 years...
But this time,
you won’t escape.
Who is he ?
Are you his master ?
He's my Corpse Puppet.
I'm an Ancestor of the Corpse Sect of Zhao.
All disciples of the Corpse Sect
must find a corpse to refine into
their Corpse Puppet.
As cultivation increases,
the Corpse Puppet will get stronger.
Your Corpse Puppet rebelled ?
Yes...
300 years ago, when I came here,
my Corpse Puppet was influenced by the Yin energy,
escaped my control
and attacked me.
The other one is my former corpse
that has somehow gained sentience...
I really need your help, young friend.
I can use a secret technique
to open a teleportation formation
directly to the Corpse Sect.
If you can activate a teleportation formation,
then why are you still here ?
I must not go further than 100 li away from my corpse
Note: 1 li = 150m
or my weak Nascent Soul
might dissipate.
I beg you, find my Senior Brother Ye Zizai and ask him to rescue me.
Adai told me that
you cultivate with Yin energy.
The Corpse Sect has secluded cultivation caves
with Earth-level Yin energy.
Young friend,
I’ll activate the formation now.
It's now up to you
to decide what you do !
The Corpse Puppet is clearly bloodthirsty...
If I don’t leave now,
I’ll be in danger
when that guy breaks in.
Agreed.
Master, this time you won’t escape !
As you may know, Daoism is not an exact science and you don't need to understand any of the inner working of chinese internal alchemy.\N\NAll you need to know is that to reach Core Formation Wang Lin needs to absorb Yin energy, condense 3 Cold Cores and fuse them together to make a Golden Core.\N\NUnderworld Yin < Earth Yin\N\NThe Ji Realm will be explained later.\N\N"To go into seclusion" is to isolate oneself for cultivation, recover from injuries, refine artifacts, etc...\N\NFor the curious:\NThere are 3 Dantian in the body located in the head, the heart and the lower abdomen (the 3 spots mentioned by the Underworld Ascension Method but with different names). In general, the Dantian is the location where spiritual energy is stored and is where cultivation happens (where a foundation is built to house a Golden Core, a Nascent Soul, an Origin Soul, etc...).\NFeel free to dig up that rabbit hole on your own if you want.
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?